DANIEL HEATHER

I am a 22-year-old undergraduate, currently in my final year of Business Studies at DCU. Through my bachelor's degree and work experience, I have developed experience in accounting and consulting. In my final year I decided to specialize in Data Analytics to round out my skillset. At school I was the Taoiseach of the student body. Personally, I am interested in basketball, MMA, fashion and history. I am a team player, with a professional approach to my responsibilities.

LEADERSHIP

While in school I was the

Taoiseach of the student body.

BUSINESS ANALYTICS

PowerBI

Tableau

Python

SQL

HTML

CORE COMPETENCIES

Problem Solving

Teamwork

Public Speaking

Initiative

Time Management

People Skills

Event Planning

CONTACT

Dublin, Ireland

086 720 5587

daniel.heather2@mail.dcu.ie

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

TAX CONSULTANT PLACEMENT · KPMG

2022-2023

- Tax Advisory: Research and draft tax advice pieces for clients. Tax residency qualification, letters to Revenue, Group structuring etc.
- Tax Compliance: Completion of tax returns for clients.
- Public Speaking: At most this involved speaking for 10 minutes to 250 people.
- Events Officer: I was heavily involved with the Events Committee and was responsible for organizing events out for 100+ attendees on a regular basis.
- Risk Management: Upkeep of risk management system of the team clients.

STORE COLLEAGUE · WOODIES

2020-2022

2020-2024

- Customer Service: Front facing customer relations on the shop floor, assisting customers with their needs and providing solutions to unique queries.
- Paint Expert: My favourite part of the job was the informal consultation process with customers. It involved discussing specific aspects of each product, figuring out what each customer needed and providing tailored advice.
- Responsibilities: Taking in weekly stock deliveries, managing the Click & Collect system and locking the store. I had my own section to restock and keep to standard.
- Problem Solving: Working within deadlines to reorganize the seasonal section to head office specifications. I was responsible for updating the seasonal section of the store regularly, rearranging it to fit head office specifications within the physical limits of our store.

EDUCATION

UNDERGRADUATE BACHELOR OF BUSINESS STUDIES

I am on track to graduate with a 1:1. I am a member of a variety of societies including Style Soc, Rock climbing, DCUInvest and MISoc.

BUSINESS ANALYTICS LANGUAGES & SKILLS

Power BI:

Expert in leveraging Power BI for comprehensive data visualization, creating interactive dashboards, and generating insightful reports. I enjoy transforming raw data into meaningful stories through analytics. I find the process satisfying from end-to-end process—starting from data exploration, through to polishing the final report.

Python:

Competent in Python for data manipulation, analysis, and visualization. Experience with Python libraries like pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, and Seaborn. Experience using scikit-learn.

Excel:

Proficiency in Excel functions, formulas, and features including pivot tables, VLOOKUP, and advanced charting. Capable of turning complex datasets into usable formats and insightful reports.

PowerPoint:

Highly skilled in creating compelling and informative presentations with PowerPoint. Strong Ability to transform complex information into clear, logical, and engaging slides. Experienced in presenting to large audiences.

Alphatax:

Proficient in the utilization of Alphatax software to complete accurate and compliant tax returns.

COURSEWORK ACCREDITATIONS

KUBICLE CERTIFICATES

Statistical Analysis

Python Fundamentals

SQL Databases

Tableau Visualizations

Excel Data Manipulation and Formatting

Excel Finance Functions